Tahnee Saunders

San Francisco

me@tahneesaunders.com

+1 (929) 228 6498

linkedin.com/in/tahneesaunders

EDUCATION

Master of Biotechnology

University of Melbourne, 2013-2014 GPA: 4.0

Bachelor of Science

University of Melbourne, 2010-2012 Major: Physiology

International Baccalaureate

Mont' Kiara International School

MBIOTECH FOCUS

Genomics and Bioinformatics Regulation of Biotechnology Data and Decision Making Metabolomics & Proteomics Microscopy for Biological Sciences Advanced Molecular Techniques Commercialization of Science

AWARDS

Dean's Honor List

Master of Biotechnology, 2014

Student Ambassador

University of Melbourne, 2013-2014

Letter of Commendation

Bachelor of Science, 2011

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

project management science communication bioinformatic analysis data visualisation literature review quantitative analysis analytical & problem solving research study design statistical analysis

KEY WORDS

collaborative multi-tasker versatile detail oriented self-motivated

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Excelling in the university environment, my next aim is to venture into industry. I have recently completed a Master of Biotechnology (with a focus on human genomics) while working as a Research Assistant in the Public Health academic sector – both of these roles have developed my skill set and ability to manage multiple ongoing projects. My previous experience will allow me to hit the ground running in a new position and add value to the right organization.

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, 2013 - current

Public Health Insight & Jack Brockhoff Foundation

University of Melbourne

- Collect, code and analyze data
- Literature reviews
- Grant applications
- Ethics applications
- Conduct and prepare surveys
- Interview transcription
- Maintain project plans & timelines
- Keep minutes from project meetings
- Complete & maintain progress reports
- Prepare presentations, posters & reports
- Manage a research database & contact list
- Obesity Prevention in Children Overview first author

Senior Demonstrator, 2013-2014

Physiology Department

University of Melbourne

- Class preparation, including set up of equipment
- Lead responsible for running of practical classes (40-60 students)

• Social Network Analysis of Public Health Promotion in Australia

• Cross-Country Research of Evidence Based Chronic Disease Prevention

- Marking assessments and providing meaningful feedback to students
- Monitoring online submissions and contribution to blogs and question forums

Masters Research Project, 2013-2014

Zoology Department

University of Melbourne

- Analysis of relaxin receptor (Rxfp1) expression in placenta & human umbilical vein endothelial cells obtained form preeclamptic and normotensive women
 - RNA and DNA isolation
- cDNA synthesis
- primer design
- RT-PCR
- gPCR
- RXFP1 expression localization to the umbilical cord
 - Paraffin embedding Microtome sectioning
 - Immunohistochemistry staining and light microscopy
- Bioinformatic search and analysis of Rxfp1 expression in pregnancy of preeclamptic and normotensive women
 - PubMed search BLAST Search Correlation analysis

Private Tutor, 2010-2014

IB Biology & Chemistry

- Mentoring Year 11 and 12 students
- Giving feedback on assignment drafts and test scores
- Teaching exam techniques and preparation methods